joomlapack.net 2011-10-27

# Privacy Policy

Thursday, 18 February 2010 11:37  Last Updated on Wednesday, 29 December 2010 16:19 

### Summary

AkeebaBackup.com is committed to protecting you and your personal information when you are using our services. We want our services to safe and enjoyable environments for our users. This Privacy Policy is relevant to our use of any personal information you provide to us during your visit to our site.

AkeebaBackup.com seeks to follow the industry's best practices concerning personal information handling.

The website contains hyperlinks to external resources, hosted and operated by third parties. These parties have their own privacy policies, including cookies, and we urge you to review them carefully. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for the handling of your personal information when visiting these external resources; your use of those third party resources and/or websites is your own responsibility.

We also use third-party service and content providers (such as Google AdSense, Google Analytics and Disqus) who may collect their own set of personal information. Since these are third parties, the information collected by them is not governed by this Privacy Statement. Take a look at the Cookies section towards the bottom of this document for more information.

### Personal information collected

Whenever you register for our members-only services, for example using our forum or registering for our newsletter, we may ask personal information about you. This can consist of such information as your name, e-mail, website address, gender, etc. By entering the information in the fields requested you enable AkeebaBackup.com to provide you with the services you select. 

We record your IP address as part of the unconditional logging our web server software does whenever anybody accesses our site. The collected IP addresses remain on record for at least a year, but they will be not shared with third parties. Exception to this rule is sharing information with authorities in the case of a suspected or proven breach of our site or other proven misuse of our services.

This website is also using "cookies" to enhance user experience. Please read the relevant chapter to find out more about our use of cookies.

### Use of collected information

AkeebaBackup.com will NOT sell, rent or otherwise willingly transmit the recorded personal information to any third party. Your privacy is important to us and we will not even offer aggregate information resulting from personal information processing to any part outside AkeebaBackup.com. We only use the recorded personal information for:

  * service administration purposes, e.g. sending you password reminders, registration confirmations, billing subscription services etc.;
  * to contact you regarding new content added on our website, e.g. new forum posts, if you have opted in for this sort of communication;
  * to personalize your experience, through the storage of your preferences in cookies and/or our site's database;
  * analyze the use of our website and improve its usability;
  * IP addresses may be used to identify the location of users, the number of visits from different cities / territories / countries or filter and block inappropriate use.

If AkeebaBackup.com wishes to use the recorded personal information for other uses, it will notify you beforehand so that you have the chance to opt-out from these new uses.

### When we contact you

We only contact you if you have explicitly opted-in for such communication through the use of our services. For example:

  * We may contact you if a new post was added to a forum thread you have subscribed to
  * We will send you a personalized copy of our newsletter if you have opted-in for it

These forms of contact are conducted by automated software running on our server. You always have the chance to opt-out from such communication. AkeebaBackup.com will never send unsolicited email messages ("spam") or allow third parties access to our users and contacts database.

We may also directly contact you - manually sending out emails, as opposed to automatic email sending outlined above - under special circumstances such as:

  * Suspecting that your account is compromised by an unauthorized third party
  * Before, during or after server-related incidents which may seriously hamper your ability to use our services
  * In case you have crossed the line of fair use of our services
  * If you have so asked us with an email, forum post, personal message, instant message, Twitter message or any other form of personal or electronic contact.

### Contact for marketing purposes

**We do not send unsolicited email messages for marketing purposes**. Subscription to our newsletter follows the industry standard rules for opt-in newsletters. This means that you have to confirm your subscription, making sure that no thrid party can subscribe you against your will, and that you can opt-out of the newsletter at any time.

### Information sharing with third parties

Information collected by AkeebaBackup.com will not be shared with any third parties. Not in their raw form, not in a processed or aggregate form. **We do not share personal information with third parties.**

_Important note_ : Please review the section on cookies, as we employ third-party service/content providers. These providers collect their own set of personal information, governed by their own privacy statements.

Exceptions to this rule will be clearly stated and will only be part of a special offer campaign. For instance, we may launch a campaign offering subscriptions to third party services for free or with a discount. If we are to collect and share your personal information you will be informed before opting in to that campaign.

### Actions for content beyond fair use and account termination policy

If the content you submit to AkeebaBackup.com is deemed offensive, inappropriate, defamatory, objectionable or in any other way engage in disruptive behavior we reserve the right to use your personal information to stop such behavior.

If AkeebaBackup.com believes on reasonable grounds that you are in violation of the laws of Greece, or the European Union directives, we reserve the right to submit your personal information - including the content itself and any other relevant information about you - to the proper authorities, such as law enforcement, your ISP or school email / ISP.

AkeebaBackup.com reserves the right to terminate user accounts (free or paid subscribers) when the aforementioned fair use rules are violated. Furthermore, AkeebaBackup.com reserves the right to terminate user accounts if the user is posting unsolicited messages (spam), engaged in sites or services promoting the unauthorized distribution of proprietary or other distributed for-a-fee software (warez), directly promoting or linking to resources promoting indecent or unlawful actions, or in any other way trying to disrupt or diminish the quality of the services offered by this site. Account termination takes place without prior notice and is considered final. Holders of terminated accounts, if they are paid subscribers, will not be refunded. AkeebaBackup.com reserves the right to terminate any further user accounts created by the holder of a terminated account, or any other person, business or organization affiliated with the holder of a terminated account.

### Zero spam tolerance

As noted above, if you send out an unsolicited message, your account will be terminated without prior notice. One strike and you're out. Moreover, you will feed our anti-spam filter with keywords so that you can't spam us again.

### Zero bandits tolerance

If you do as much as imply that you are encouraging people to use illegal or unofficial copies of software your account will be terminated without prior notice, as noted above. Respect the work of others and we'll respect you. If you don't and act as a bandit, you'll be treated as one.

### Privacy policy for minors

If you are considered a minor in your jurisdiction (for example, people under 18 years of age in Greece) you must get your parent's/guardian's permission before submitting any content or personal information to AkeebaBackup.com. If you or your parent/guardian believes beyond doubt that such information have been submitted in violation of the above term, you may submit to us relevant proof so that we can remove the offending information from our website and records.

### Duration of personal information retainment

Notwithstanding any aforementioned cases of explicit information removal, your personal information may be stored in our servers for an indefinite period of time, no less than the duration of your account's existence or 1 calendar year, whichever is more.

### Use of cookies

**What is a cookie?** A cookie is a brief amount of data, usually containing a unique identifier, sent to your browser software from a website and recorded on your computer's permanent storage. Each website may set one or several such cookies on your computer, but your browser will only allow a website to access the cookie(s) it has set and deny access to other websites' cookies.

Cookies record information about your preferences and allow us to customize your experience. They are also used for handling user authentication in the members-only areas of a website. Users have the option to be forewarned before accepting a cookie, review cookies already stored on their computer's permanent storage and even delete them if so required. These options are given to you by your web browser software. Each web browser handles these features in a different way, so you have to consult your web browser's help / user guide / manual to learn more about this.

**How cookies are used on AkeebaBackup.com?** AkeebaBackup.com uses cookies to track your preferences regarding our site's features, including the forum and the "remember me" login feature. We also use cookies to authenticate you to members-only features. If you block AkeebaBackup.com's cookies you may not be able to use our members-only features as a consequence.

**Third-party cookies.** AkeebaBackup.com employs the services of third-party services and content provides. Most notably we use Google AdSense to display ads, Google Analytics to track website usage. Each of these services sets its own cookies. AkeebaBackup.com doesn't have direct access to those cookies and the use of those third-part cookies is governed solely by the respective service/content provider's Privacy Statement. For more information you may consult the following resources:

  * [Google privacy center](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html "Google  privacy center"). Information on use of cookies by Google AdSense and Google Analytics, as well as information from opting-out of the collection of such information.

### Contact information

If you have any question regarding our privacy policy you may contact us by one of the following means:

  * Sending an email to nicholas at this domain name
  * Posting on our forum's General Discussion section
  * Sending a tweet or a Twitter direct message to @nikosdion or @akeebabackup

Alternatively, you can use the "Contact Us" link on the bottom of every page of this site.
